When I started my PT business,
before I had the social media following,
I was
practicing by going into local businesses.
I actually was at a business event,
and I was asked, "Oh, James,
where's the gym
you work in?" I was like,
"Bracknell." They were like, "Oh,
there's a big business
park in Bracknell. How far
are you from that?" I was like,
"I'm in it.
I'm right slap bang in the middle of
that technology park, brother." He goes,
"Oh,
so you're telling me there's no local
businesses that you could walk into in
your
lunch break and ask them
if they wanted a free seminar on fat
loss?" I said, "I
probably could do that." I shit you not,
the very first business I went into,
they were like, "Oh,
we'd love that." Booked me in.
Now, there were only about 11 people
that turned up to it, but they gave me a
little boardroom. Eleven people came in.
That was my biggest crowd at that point.
Eleven people were there.
I got to practice the process of giving my
first talk, and at the end of it,
three of them inquired about PT, and two
of them ended up as clients.
So I didn't have to go into
that business and ask
that. But for so many of you,
are there businesses?
Are there technology parks?
And again,
there'll be different flyers for this.
The ones who go out to residential might
say, "Hey, me and my daughters, me and my
kids," or just that,
"I've been in your area from a local road
giving out things.
Are you interested?" From a commercial
standpoint, "Hey, my name's James.
I'm a personal trainer.
For the next six months,
I'm taking two hours out of my day
to approach local businesses to educate
their workforce how they can eat better
and
train more, so that, one,
they can feel and look better.
But two,
so they can be more productive in the
workforce." The business is going,
"Let's book him in.
It's going to cost us nothing, and
if them lot could be less
fat,
we could get more work out of them." Then
they go to HR, and HR go to people
and say, "Hey, guys,
we really care about the levels of health
and wellbeing and mental health in our
office.
So for that reason,
we've gone to large expense to get in a
health
expert to help you guys with your diet."
That's how the corporate thing works.
So from a proactivity standpoint,
humanization standpoint, these are great.
These things can get an emotional
connection.
Putting something on the side of your car
isn't.
Now,
paid ads can circumnavigate social media
because you can just
pay-to-play, as they say.
You could just pay for traffic to go to
your website,
pay for traffic to go to your landing
page,
pay for traffic to go to your squeeze
page, whatever it is. However,
I do like people to master organic
first.
Don't just see paid ads as the lady with
the red dress in "The Matrix" that
walks past and takes your eye line.
If you are going to get into the paid ads,
I would recommend that you get good at
organic content,
because your ability to conduct yourself,
get your point across,
everything you need to do in a paid ad,
also, you need to get good at in organic
content. So trust me, if you
are going to do paid ads, it needs to be
synergistic with organic content.
Not to mention that people often,
through paid ads,
want to see some social proof.
If you're someone
that just turned up in a paid ad,
they're like, "I want to know
more about this person.
If I'm going to spend my money,
I want to see this person
move and do other things." And
if you've got a dormant, dead social media
profile and you're spending loads in paid
ads, when they come to your page and you
haven't posted in six weeks,
they're going to think,
"This person's a charlatan
who's going to run away with my money." So
you do really need to make sure that if
you're going to do paid strategy,
it needs to be coupled with organic.
I'm just saying.